If you can avoid drinking
it, I'd prefer you don't.
I wouldn't mind you being an undead forever.
Just stay here forever and spend
your life as an adventurer.
Lorraine...
But that's not what you want, right?
Even if you don't have the talent,
even if it takes you years...
You want to become one
no matter what, right?
A Mythril-class adventurer...
Don't pretend you haven't
already made your decision.
This has been your dream
for years, hasn't it?
Yes.
Ever since I was a child.
What's wrong?
No, don't worry about it.
I just remembered something Sheila asked me.
What did she ask you?
Don't worry about it.
Now that you've said that, I'm worried.
Really worried.
Fine, I'll tell you.
I'll tell you, but if you don't
want to answer, you don't have to.
You know everything about
me there is to know, don't you?
I don't.
There's a ton I don't know.
Rentt, why did you decide to become
a Mythril-class adventurer?
Rentt
Faina
I never told you?
I've known you for long enough that
I kind of expected that answer...
Whatever.
Just drink the blood of
a vampire, or a troll,
or whatever you want, and evolve already!
That's kind of mean, isn't it?
"It's wrong to ask an adventurer
about their identity or past."
"That's the unspoken rule of this job."
You're the one who told me
that all those years ago.
Of course, I can't imagine you having
any kind of dark secret in your past.
But after you told me that,
I couldn't exactly ask you.
It just never came up, really...
It's not that interesting a story, anyway.
Revenge...
No, that's not quite right.
I wanted to become a person who could
stop a tragedy from ever happening.
Rentt.
The village where I was
born, Hathala Village,
was nestled deep in the mountains
far away from any city.
My dad did the shopping for the whole village,
and anything else that required going outside.
I was five the first time my
parents took me outside.
Hey, Rentt.
What, Jinlin?
What do you think the town's like?
I'm sure there's lots of
stuff we've never seen!
I can't wait!
There's a lot of people, right?
I'm scared of bandits and stuff.
You're such a wimp, Rentt.
If you're...
If you're that wimpy you'll never
be able to become an adventurer.
Adventurer?
Shh!
Don't let your parents hear!
Okay...
I want to travel the world when I grow up!
Waterfalls falling from islands
floating in the sky...
Towns surrounded by water...
Castles that disappear like a mirage...
There's a lot of amazing places, they say.
But it sounds dangerous.
Don't worry! I'll get
strong and protect you!
I was really shy back then.
That's a surprise.
I'd envisioned you swinging a wooden
sword and practicing every day.
That would’ve been Jinlin.
She dragged me all around the town.
We got one heck of a scolding
from Granny later.
But looking back, it was fun.
We were attacked on the way back.
By him.
Granny!
Get away from here, now...
Granny! Granny!
Rentt!
Maybe it was an awful thing
to do, leaving them behind.
But we were sure...
...that we were the only survivors.
It has to have given up by now.
Yeah.
It's a horrible thought, looking back.
The wolf monster was toying with us.
Jinlin! Why?
'cause I promised... I'd protect you.
Get stronger, Rentt.
Get back.
I'll handle him.
You still want a fight?
You okay?
Why...
Why didn't you come sooner?
I'm sorry. This is my fault.
If I'd only gotten here sooner...
After he drove the wolf off,
the adventurer carried everyone's
bodies back to the village.
Oh, there you are.
Hey...
How can I become an adventurer?
Why?
My friend wanted to become one.
So...
I see.
Rentt, how old are you?
Five...
I'm sorry, but you need to be 15 to
register with the Adventurers Guild.
So train hard in this village
for the next ten years.
First, you need to learn to fight well enough to battle a monster.
And knowledge, you'll need that, too!
Learn to read, write, and do arithmetic.
Herbs, magic, and how to survive
when you're in the wild.
There must be hunters and old
herbalists in this village.
First, start by persuading
them to teach you.
I was surprised.
Most grown-ups would just say, "Good luck!"
But not him.
And if I do all that, can
I be a strong adventurer?
I can't promise that.
Knowledge and combat skill will
only get you to the starting line.
After that, it's up to how
much effort you put in.
Effort...
Remember one more thing.
My name is Wilfried Ryukker.
A Mythril-class adventurer.
Mythril...
When you become an adventurer, come see me.
I don't know where I'll be
in a decade, of course...
But as long as I'm alive, I'll
probably be an adventurer.
Listen. Don't die until you
make your dream come true.
I won't!
So that's why.
It happens a lot, way
out in the countryside.
So the "certain person" you
mentioned long ago, was...
Yes, that adventurer.
I don't know if you have
good luck or bad luck.
The odds of randomly being saved
by a Mythril-class adventurer
are about the same as the odds
of encountering a dragon.
You've got that right.
So you learned your kindness from him, huh?
I'm sure he was a nice guy,
but he must've understood...
Understood what?
Without a goal, I wasn't going
to get back my will to live.
I see.
So that's why he made his advice
as specific as he could, huh?
I assume so.
Someday I'll defeat the monster
that killed my parents and Jinlin.
After I become a Mythril-class
adventurer, like Wilfried.
A decade in the village, a decade in Maalt.
You've spent 20 years at this, huh?
And never got above Bronze, though.
I'm scared to die.
But...
If you give up, you're as good as dead.
I knew you were only
pretending to be uncertain.
Well, that's who you are.
Don't worry. I'll give your
bones a proper burial.
That's about all I can do for you.
I'm sorry.
If something happens to me and
I lose control, burn me to ash.
I'm praying that won't happen.
Rentt...
I'm fine, at least for now.
Looks like the blood was fake...
Hey, Rentt! What's wrong?
Keep control of yourself, Rentt!
Rentt!
What is this sensation?
It's like my body is being remade...
I... I...
I don't want to become
one of those monsters!
I...
Rentt.
You have a dream... a goal, dont you?
So...
Come back.
It's not gonna be worth a damn
without orichalcum, huh?
You don't have to start this early, darling.
Oh, it's for him, isn't it?
But didn't you just give him a sword?
I can't tell, but he's gotten
a lot stronger, hasn't he?
Yeah.
He's even picked up some weird tricks.
Then we need to make
him a worthy sword.
I have been defeated!
Hey, let me be an adventurer, next!
I'll be the wizard, then!
What? I'm the monster again?
Oh my. Such a brave knight.
Or an adventurer, perhaps?
You need to be in bed, Headmistress Lilian!
I'm fine.
I feel wonderful today.
May I eat with you all today?
Of course.
Everyone will be overjoyed.
Thank you, Alize.
It's thanks to you that
I'm doing better now.
That's not true, Headmistress Lilian.
Everyone... everyone helped!
Morning!
Okay, I'm first here again today!
Ryze!
Wait up!
Are you okay, Laura?
Good morning.
Good morning!
We have a whole bunch of new jobs today!
It was worth coming early!
Yeah! Let's go, Rina!
Anything good, Ryze?
I still can't read some of these
letters, but how about this one?
The pay's good.
No way! It says it's the second floor.
That's right. Only take jobs that
are a good fit for your strength.
How about this one?
Hmm... seems good to me!
Right?
Everyone, be careful if you're
going to the labyrinth.
It's important to turn back if
even the slightest thing feels off.
Yes, we'll remember that.
An adventurer must never
let their guard down!
Right!
And... you only get one shot at life!
I want a little more sleep...
It's been so long since I've felt sleepy...
Ever since I became an undead,
it was like my whole body was
empty, down to my heart.
But with each evolution,
I gained organs... skin...
That horrible feeling... the pain...
The fear and despair at becoming
something that wasn't me...
I guess I only endured it
because I was immortal, huh?
What are you reading?
You're awake?
Yeah...
I was reading a book about vampire ecology.
Ghast. Lesser vampire. Middle. Greater.
The more powerful they become,
the rarer it is to see one.
And the harder it becomes to classify them.
Why are you reading that?
That's an easy question to answer.
Basically...
Congratulations on your evolution.
What did I become?
I'll check for you.
Start by taking off your clothes.
What are these?
Wings?
You can shrink them by
focusing on them, huh?
That's good for you.
It sure is.
I never would've been able
to go out in public again.
Hey, so what did I become?
I don't know.
But whatever it is, it's
a more powerful being.
I assume it's one of the
weaker types of vampires,
but I've never heard of one with wings.
I see.
I'll look into the wings later.
Start by showing me your face.
Okay.
Open your mouth.
I see small fangs...
You're very likely a vampire, then.
Now the top.
Okay.
Well?
Your eyes are red.
That's something vampires
are well known for,
but there are also humans with red eyes.
On its own, that's not enough
for you to be found out.
More importantly...
It feels like a face I haven't
seen in a long time.
I know it's late, but there's something
I want to say to that face.
What?
What else?
Welcome home, Rentt Faina.
Thanks.
I'm home.
Sorry to drag you out here with me.
It's fine. It's my thanks for
everything you've done for me.
Hey, did you ever go see Wilfried?
I looked for him a bunch, but he's
not in this country, I think.
Another country, then.
But it's dangerous for a Bronze-class
to go on long journeys alone, right?
True.
And part of me didn't want to go until
I felt a bit more worthy, actually.
And that's why you haven't
gone to see him for 20 years.
Yeah, that's right.
Thanks.
But right now, I could go.
I could go see him.
Do what you want.
You don't listen to a word I say, after all.
You'll get a chance sometime, I'm sure.
Yeah.
I wouldn't mind coming along
if I'm not doing anything.
Glad to hear it.